Archers!
EAST GATE
This is a fight to the death.
There's no need to think about surviving!
Xiao Heng, you've been abandoned!
Who said he's abandoned?
Hold your arrows!
Stop looking. There are no reinforcements.
It's just me.
Do you have a death wish?
I told you, I won't abandon you.
I'd come to you.
I've fulfilled my life's purpose.
I have no more regrets.
I, Xue Fangfei, have no regrets
in dying for Great Yan today.
Shen Yurong, I'll allow you
to kill me once more today.
Xue Li,
I once wanted
to sacrifice myself for Great Yan,
but the imperial family
could crush you and me
as if we were ants.
Would anyone remember what I did?
No!
So what's the point of us
dying for Great Yan?
No one will remember.
Xue Li,
kill Xiao Heng
and we'll live on,
just like we used to.
Shen Yurong,
you're wrong.
Someone will remember.
Prince Cheng abandoned
Wang City in the north and retreated,
disregarding the people.
At the valley passage, to ensure
the people could evacuate safely,
a hundred Longwu soldiers
fought to the death,
not thinking of surviving.
We remember the names of the soldiers!
We call the 100 heroic spirits
of Longwu soldiers outside Wang City!
Xiao Minghan!
General Xiao.
Peng Guang!
Vice General Peng.
Zhao Decheng!
My brother.
Huang Junchu!
Zhang Che!
Li Licheng!
Qian Ziming!
The loyal soul of Great Yan, Xiao Heng!
Xue Fangfei!
Stop it!
Archers!
Shen Yurong, I'll show you
what the army of Great Zhao
is capable of today.
Yang Qing, get ready for battle.
Yang Qing!
The fish talisman is here
and those who disobey my order will die!
Longwu Army, come with me.
Duke Su, a military order must be obeyed.
The Longwu Army only acknowledges
the fish talisman.
Xiao Heng, look at the Longwu Army here.
Do you really want to kill them?
Don't listen to his crap.
Why don't we strike first?
Among these soldiers
are those your father personally guided.
The army of Great Zhao is your ally.
Are you really going
to let your allied forces
fight against the Longwu Army?
Xiao Heng, you've been so arrogant
all your life and were never defeated.
But in the end,
you couldn't protect anyone.
How can you compete with me?
The holder of the fish talisman shall die!
Longwu Army, remove your armor!
Xue Li,
your hands are for playing the guqin,
not for holding arrows.
You're the one
who forced me to learn archery.
Yang Qing!
Whoever disobeys
will die!
Focus on the target. I'll count to three.
Together, let's release
the thumb that's pulling the string.
Remember, don't hesitate.
One,
two,
three.
Xiao Heng, catch it.
How did you know
the names of these people?
General Xiao told me.
Xiao Heng,
can you let it go now?
Xiao Heng, lead General Xiao's Longwu Army
to fight our way back.
Duke Su,
please lead the Longwu Army
to fight our way back!
- Fight our way back!
Take revenge for General Xiao!
- Revenge!
Take revenge
for the fallen Longwu warriors!
Avenge the fallen Longwu warriors!
Take revenge
for the fallen Longwu warriors!
- Revenge!
Jiuyue, please lead your troops
to wipe out rebels outside the city.
Leave that to me.
I'll wait for your return.
Longwu Army, listen up!
- Yes!
Fight our way back to the capital
and wipe out rebels from the north!
Xue Li,
you still can't bear to kill me.
You still love me.
There's no love
or hatred
between us anymore.
I just want to see you
get your karma.
If you want to see me get my karma,
you should have killed me.
Kill me,
so I can pay you back
everything I owe you.
I'd have no regrets
if I die at your hands.
Killing you would dirty my hands.
You're a traitor to Great Yan.
The law of Great Yan
should be the one to carry out your karma.
Xue Li,
back then,
if I didn't become the top scorer
and lived a good life with you
in Huaixiang instead,
would we not have to go through all this?
I, Shen Yurong, have only made
one mistake in my life.
But this one mistake leaves me
with no way to turn back anymore.
Shen Yurong,
in your next life,
I hope you'll be born noble
as you wish
and be a good person.
Zhao Ye, what kind of emperor
hides in there like you?
You don't deserve to sit on that throne.
Give up your throne
and I'll leave your body intact!
Your Highness, the Longwu Army
have charged into the palace.
Longwu Army?
Shen Yurong is useless.
Just surrender.
Xiao Heng, you're better than your father.
How dare you mention General Xiao?
I'm going to avenge General Xiao
and the fallen 100 Longwu soldiers today!
- Attack!
Now that you know all about it,
you should know
that he was the one who got in my way!
In order to cover up your crime
of abandoning the people,
you harmed my father,
abandoned him outside of Wang City,
and blocked his way back to the city!
You caused 100 Longwu soldiers
to die in vain!
How can a man like you
be worthy of the throne?
- Yang Qing!
- Yes!
Arrest the traitors!
Wait.
Take her here.
One more step
and I'll kill her.
This is Zhao Ye's favorite consort.
I'll see who dares to do
anything reckless.
Xiao Heng, tell Zhao Ye
that next year, I'll make sure he dies.
Duke Su,
please don't tell His Majesty
about the palace maid.
I'm taking this secret with me.
Xiao Heng, you can't kill me.
I'm your father's disciple.
I'm his only disciple.
I'm not my father.
This sword in my hand
doesn't know you!
HENING GATE
"Prince Cheng Zhao Sheng
colluded with Princess Wanning
to kill loyal officials,
extort money from the people,
commit bribery, and usurp the throne.
These are grave crimes."
After Prince Cheng's death,
his remaining followers in the north
started a rebellion in the name
of seeking justice for him.
Ye Shijie wrote a diatribe
against Prince Cheng
and the Eldest Princess.
COURT OF JUDICIAL REVIEW NOTICE
In the name of suppressing rebels,
the Imperial Court sent troops
to suppress the northern army.
Li Zhongnan and his family
were arrested for treason
and sentenced to death.
- Go!
- Shen Yurong's assets were confiscated.
His mother and Shen Ruyun,
who returned to their hometown,
were arrested and questioned.
Jiang Yuanxing and his family
are removed from the Jiang family tree.
- Mother!
Don't kick us out, Mother!
General Xiao orders Xiao Heng around
to serve him tea and drinks
on the grounds that he was
seriously injured when saving me.
The capital is finally at peace.
TAIJI HALL
GOVERN PEOPLE, SERVE THE HEAVENS
I heard
she even left a message before she died.
She asked me
not to tell you about the palace maid.
Your Majesty, the Longwu Army is ready.
When are you going to depart?
Two days later.
Take all the troops
in the south of the city.
And my imperial guards too.
Since Prince Cheng is dead,
Dai will attack us in full force.
I won't rest assured
if you only take the Longwu Army.
I can't take
Great Yan's strongest forces away
while Prince Cheng's followers
are still at large.
Besides,
my father protected Great Yan
with only the Longwu Army.
I can't lose to him.
My lady,
we've got good news.
Magistrate Xue remembers everything now.
You mean…
He has come to his senses.
He remembers all of us.
Go and check on him.
Mr. Xue Zhao is already inside.
Xue Li has suffered.
I'm unfilial.
I caused you and Xue Zhao
a lot of suffering
and injustice.
It's all my fault.
I'm sorry, Father.
- No. It's not your fault.
- I'm sorry, Father.
Get up quickly. Get up.
I don't blame you.
It's not your fault.
After everything that happened,
I realized
that you're not the same little kid
who was bullied in my memories.
Even if a bigger obstacle comes your way,
you'll be able to withstand it.
Now that I've come to my senses,
I won't let you suffer anymore.
Father.
When are we going back to Huaixiang?
Father, we can't go back to Huaixiang yet
because I'm still the second daughter
of the Jiang family.
I haven't explained
this matter clearly yet.
Father, I told you,
but you wouldn't believe me.
Xue Li has my brother-in-law now.
How can she be willing to go with us?
Xue Zhao.
All right.
I've heard about Duke Su.
Father.
You've got good taste.
He's a good man.
Whatever you do, I will support you.
Don't be afraid even if you failed once,
and don't let that deter you.
You have to forget
what happened and move on.
No matter what, I have your back.
All right.
Mr. Xue has completely recovered?
He even praised you.
What did he say?
He said…
Ask him yourself later on.
What about you?
What is your plan for the future?
Duke Su,
your mansion is a bit shabby.
It's time for a renovation.
Why are you suddenly talking about that?
Take your time to figure it out.
What do you mean?
There is a man I love.
And he is…
right in front of me.
Have I been ordering him around too much
in the past two days?
Has he gone silly?
- What could he be thinking?
- That's possible.
- Do you think he's--
- You're the silly ones!
Let me tell you.
I need to renovate my mansion.
Keep an eye on it.
Why do you want to renovate it?
Because I want to renovate it,
that's why I want to renovate it.
TOMB OF JIANG LI, TOMB OF TONG'ER
After deliberating it,
this should be your favorite place.
Miss.
Li'er.
Miss, thank you
for clearing
my ruined reputation.
Li'er,
I'd do what I promised you.
The flowers are so beautiful.
BEST WISHES
EAST GATE
CAPITAL OF YAN
JIANG RESIDENCE
I've already resigned from my post
with His Majesty today.
I'm planning to leave the capital
the day after tomorrow to go to Yongzhou.
What's your plan?
I've married Xiao Heng.
I'll wait for him at the Duke's Mansion.
What if he can't make it back?
If he can't make it back,
I'll tie my hair and be a widow
for the rest of my life.
But he promised me he'd come back.
Then do as you wish.
Father.
There's something else
I want to confess to you.
Do you want to tell me
that you're not Jiang Li,
but…
Xue Fangfei?
Was Li'er
in pain
when she passed away?
Did anyone stay by her side?
When…
she passed away,
Tong'er and I
were by her side.
She passed away peacefully.
She didn't suffer from any pain.
She didn't suffer from sickness.
I think she has already reunited
with Madam Ye.
I hope
that this matter stays between you and me.
Don't tell anyone else.
Your grandmother is old.
She can't handle this news.
I got it,
Father.
All right.
MORAL EXCELLENCE
LEISURELY AND ELEGANT RESIDENCE
JIANG RESIDENCE
Jiang Li,
Duke Su won't be back soon.
Why don't you come with us
to Yongzhou first?
Yes, have you thought this through?
Come with us.
What's the fun of staying
in the capital by yourself?
Also, Ruoyao is waiting
to meet us in Yongzhou.
I've heard she has improved a lot lately.
She'll surely show off in front of me.
Jiang Li, if you're not around,
I'm afraid I can't beat her.
Come with us.
You guys go first.
When you two are settled in Yongzhou,
I'll go and visit you.
All right. Stop trying to persuade her.
Li'er has her own ideas.
Take good care of yourself in the capital.
If you need anything, write to me anytime.
Uncle Yuanping,
Aunt Lu,
take care.
Take care of yourself too.
Shijie.
JIANG RESIDENCE
My good buddy,
thanks for seeing me off.
- Take care.
I'll miss you.
Take care.
Let's go.
Jiang Jingrui,
take good care of Liu Xu.
Don't worry. Let's go.
We'll get going.
Be careful.
JIANG RESIDENCE
Grandmother, take care.
Now, just do whatever you want.
Just remember,
if you have any problems,
come to us in Yongzhou.
I also wish you
a prosperous life in Yongzhou.
All the best.
All right.
Take good care of yourself.
Father.
It's getting cold.
Don't forget to wear more clothes.
Don't catch a cold.
You're going back to Duke's Mansion,
aren't you?
I'll give you a ride.
- I…
- Mr. Jiang has left the capital,
but I'm still here.
If you need anything in the future,
you can come to me anytime.
- You know I'm not…
- My cousin.
You don't have an elder brother.
Think of me as your own elder brother
from now on.
My brother.
Let's go.
All right.
JIANG RESIDENCE
Must you go?
Prince Cheng has been eliminated
and Dai has amassed a huge army,
thinking it's the best time
to invade Great Yan.
We have to confront them head-on
and break their delusion.
Only when the nation is safe
and the people are well
will we be happy.
When will you be back?
The day the wintersweet blossoms
will be the day
I safely return in triumph.
PLANTED WITH MY WIFE
ON SPRING, MAY OF THE 13TH YEAR
- Kill!
Lu Ji!
I'll bring you home!
I'll take you home!
Wen Ji!
Wen Ji.
I'll bring you both home.
Don't shoot him!
I want to capture Xiao Heng alive!
RETURN TO THE CLOUDS
When will you be back?
The day the wintersweet blossoms
will be the day
I safely return in triumph.
PLANTED WITH MY WIFE ON SPRING,
MAY OF THE 13TH YEAR